Henry M. Beach Adirondack Camp Photographs
Henry M. Beach Adirondack Camp Photographs
Undated
Beach, Henry M., 1863-1943.
53 items.
Noted Adirondack photographer. Collection contains 53 photographs of camps in the Adirondacks region of New York State, including Old Forge, Saranac Lake, Big Moose, Raquette Lake, more.
2746138
Biographical History
Henry M. Beach (1863-1943) was a prolific and accomplished upstate New York photographer who documented the North Country during the first quarter of the twentieth century. Adirondack Vernacular: The Photography of Henry M. Beach, a collection of his work, was published by Syracuse University Press in 2003.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Henry M. Beach Adirondack Camp Photographs consists of 53 photogaphs of camps in the Adirondacks region of New York State. Areas represented include Big Moose, Raquette Lake, Saranac Lake, Old Forge, Star Lake, Utica and more. The photos are panoramic prints approximately 9" by 36".
Arrangement of the Collection
No particular order.
Subject and Genre Headings
New York State; Photography; Beach, Henry M., 1863-1943.; Cities and towns -- New York (State) -- Adirondack Mountains Region -- Photographs.; Hunting lodges -- Photographs.; Adirondack Mountains (N.Y.) -- Photographs.; Old Forge (N.Y.) -- Photographs.; Raquette Lake (N.Y.) -- Photographs.; Saranac Lake (N.Y.) -- Photographs.; Photographs.; Photographers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Unspecified, 2004.
Inventory
- Adirondacks region photographs
  - Adirondack League Club, Little Moose Lake, Old Forge, New York, 1914; PHB 01-006-359; Slightly different view than print that is titled; 32-1/2" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - View of Sunset Camp on Raquette Lake, Raquette Lake, New York, 1914; PHB 02-005-119; 28" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Large panoramic view of Fulton Chain of Lakes, Old Forge, New York, 1911; PHB 03-006-364; 43-3/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - View of Sunset Camp on Raquette Lake, Raquette Lake, New York, 1914; PHB 04-005-123; 26-3/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Panoramic view of village of Deferiet, Deferiet, New York, 1910; PHB 05-005-360; Several houses along with post office and general store; 36-1/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Taken from veranda of Grand View Hotel looking east, Lake Placid, New York, 1912; PHB 06-005-362; 38-1/2" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Mountain view of Eagle Bay and Inlet, Fourth Lake, Old Forge, New York, 1911; PHB 07-006-389; 28-1/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Unidentified at this point, but is early paper mill on river, Possibly Deferiet, New York?, 1910; PHB 08-005-390; 42" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Upper Saranac Lake, New York, 1912; PHB 09-012-365; Copyright Deposit; H. M. Beach; February 19, 1912; 41" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Old Forge, New York, 1914; PHB 10-008-140; 32-1/2" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Close up of heart shaped garden, main drive at Kamp Kill Kare, Lake Kora, New York, 1914; PHB 11-005-143; 22-3/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - View from lake of walking bridge to Kamp Kill Kare, Lake Kora, New York, 1914; PHB 12-007-366; 38-3/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - View of Saranac Inn across lake, Upper Saranac Lake, New York, 1911; PHB 13-005-149; 26-1/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Bird's eye view of Fulton Chain of Lakes, Old Forge, New York, 1911; PHB 14-005-152; Copyright Deposit; H. M. Beach; July 18, 1911; 42-1/2" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Excellent panoramic view from lake of main camp, boathouses and cabins, Big Moose, New York, 1914; PHB 15-006-155; 36-1/2" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Resort Hotel and Casino, Long Lake, New York, 1914; PHB 16-007-317; 27-1/2" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Close up view of main camp and boathouses at Dart's Camp with what, Big Moose, New York, 1914; PHB 17-006-161; Appears to be Bill Dart with his dog and cat standing near Dart's Lake shore; 38-1/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Lake Placid, New York, 1912; PHB 18-007-166; 28-3/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Panoramic view of Grand View Hotel looking southeast, Lake Placid, New York, 1912; PHB 19-006-172; Copyright Deposit; H. M. Beach; February 19, 1912; 41" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - View from mountain of lake with two gentleman relaxing after, 1914; PHB 20-008-367; Possibly carrying H. M. Beach's Panoramic Camera up mountain; 44" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - View of Upper Saranac Lake with Wawbeek buildings to right and Wawbeek launch on lake, Upper Saranac Lake, New York, 1912; PHB 21-014-368; Copyright Deposit; H. M. Beach; February 19, 1912; 33-1/2" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Close up view from lawn of original Seventh Lake House and boats on Seventh Lake, Inlet, New York, 1911; PHB 22-09-322; Copyright Deposit; H. M. Beach; July 18, 1911; 25-1/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Close up of main camp and boat house with Mr. & Mrs. Henry Covey on lawn, Big Moose, New York, 1911; PHB 23-009-401; With guide boat on Big Moose Lake and three gentlemen in background; 32" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Close up of Glennmore Hotel with steamer "Big Moose" leaving dock, Big Moose, New York, 1911; PHB 24-006-195; Copyright Deposit; H. M. Beach; September 11, 1911; 40" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Close up of Glennmore Hotel with people on porch, horses, carriages and early car, Big Moose, New York, 1911; PHB 25-00-199; Copyright Deposit; H. M. Beach; September 11, 1911; 40-1/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Close up view of Lake Placid Club boathouses, Lake Placid, New York, 1912; PHB 26-006-204; 39-3/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Close up view from lake of Kamp Kill Kare bridge and buildings, Lake Kora, New York, 1914; PHB 27-005-209; 31" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Veranda of Grand View Hotel looking east, Lake Placid, New York, 1912; PHB 28-005-212; Copyright Deposit; H. M. Beach; February 19, 1912; 36" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - View of mountains from grounds of Grand View Hotel with, Lake Placid, New York, 1912; PHB 29-006-218; Groves of trees and baseball grounds labeled; 42" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Camps, man in boat, docks on Fourth Lake, Old Forge, New York, 1913; PHB 30-007-402; 40-1/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Third Lake, Old Forge, New York, 1911; PHB 31-008-370; Copyright Deposit; H. M. Beach; July 18, 1911; 29-1/4" x 6 (Map-case 77)
  - Shoreline and lake view, Star Lake, New York, 1911; PHB 32-005-230; 31-3/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Large panoramic view of the Fulton Chain of Lakes, Old Forge, New York, 1911; PHB 33-009-374; 39-1/2" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - View of main camp, boathouse and cabins overlooking Dart's Lake, Big Moose, New York, 1914; PHB 34-007-328; 36-1/2" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Political Rally, August 21, 1912, James Sherman, Vice President, Utica, New York, PHB 35-005-240; Under Taft giving campaign speech; 32-1/2" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - View of buildings and lake from lawn at Kamp Kill Kare, Lake Kora, New York, 1914; PHB 36-007-392; 30-3/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Formerly located on the West Side of Stillwater Reservoir, 1914; PHB 37-011-403; 29-1/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Looking to East over Mirror Lake, Lake Placid Club on far shore, Lake Placid, New York, 1912; PHB 38-010-394; 26-1/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - View from lawn showing hotel, pines, lawn, tennis court and drive, Lake Placid, New York, 1912; PHB 39-008-372; Copyright Deposit; H. M. Beach; February 16, 1912; 40-3/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Main lodge and cabins on Big Moose Lake, Big Moose, New York, 1911; PHB 40-009-377; Copyright Deposit; H. M. Beach; September 21, 1911; 35-3/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Panoramic view from mountain of Big Moose Lake, Big Moose, New York, 1914; PHB 41-009-396; 33-1/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - View of and from the veranda, Lake Bonaparte, New York, 1910; PHB 42-008-380; Excellent panoramic view of The New Hermitage Hotel; 36-1/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Upper Saranac Lake, New York, 1912; PHB 44-005-275; 20-3/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - View of Lake Placid Club, Lake Placid, New York, 1911; PHB 45-017-398; 20-1/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Close up of buildings at Kamp Kill Kare, Lake Kora, New York, 1914; PHB 46-005-287; 10" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Group of people overlooking Fourth Lake from Rocky Mountain, Old Forge, New York, 1911; PHB 47-007-292; 23-1/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Close up view of Kamp Kill Kare gardens, Lake Kora, New York, 1914; PHB 48-005-295; 13-1/2" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Close up view of greenhouse and gardens with gardener working at Kamp Kill Kare, Lake Kora, New York, 1914; PHB 49-005-298; 17-1/2" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Looking East over Mirror Lake, Lake Placid, New York, 1911; PHB 50-006-400; 16-1/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Saranac Inn, Upper Saranac Lake, New York, 1911; PHB 51-006-383; 18-1/2" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - View from mountain of Eagle Bay, Fourth Lake, Old Forge, New York, 1911; PHB 52-007-381; 17-3/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - View of Buttermilk Falls on Raquette River, New York, 1914; PHB 53-008-385; 20-1/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)
  - Ogdensburg State Mental Hospital, Ogdensburg, New York, 1910; PHB 54-005-386; 13-3/4" x 6" (Map-case 77)